{
    "id": "f46b5596ab23444eb7d457e2c34109c0",
    "title": "Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I want to know why ………………………….. late.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the subject goes before the verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "are you",
                "you are",
                "you"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had asked me, I …………………………….. her.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will tell",
                "would tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She would have come if you …………………………….. her.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "inform",
                "informed",
                "had informed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We are looking forward ……………………………. you.",
            "description": "Write to + ing form after look forward/looking forward. ",
            "answers": [
                "of meeting",
                "to meet",
                "to meeting"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The more you praise him the more arrogant …………………………..",
            "description": "The same pattern is used in both clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "becomes he",
                "he becomes",
                "does he become"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The louder you speak ………………………………. you confuse me.",
            "description": "The + comparative is used in both clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "more",
                "the more",
                "the most"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind …………………………… me your pen?",
            "description": "Ing forms or if-clauses are used after would you mind.",
            "answers": [
                "to lending",
                "lending",
                "to lend"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… you study well, you cannot pass.",
            "description": "If is grammatically correct in that sentence, but it does not make logical sense. ",
            "answers": [
                "Unless",
                "If",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This boy is ………………………… to work.",
            "description": "Note the pattern too...to...",
            "answers": [
                "very lazy",
                "so lazy",
                "too lazy"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were the king, you ………………………………. my queen.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use past simple in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is very fond ……………………………. her cats and dogs.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "to",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He enjoys ……………………………….. with children.",
            "description": "Write an ing form after enjoy. ",
            "answers": [
                "to play",
                "playing",
                "to playing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}